https://www.clearly.com.au/privacy-policy

Skip to main content
Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy is to inform you of what personal data we, Clearly, collect from you when you visit our website or use our services. This document will further explain why we collect it, and what we do with it. Your personal data
refers to any information relating to you, specifically with regard to your name and contact details including your home address, telephone number, and email address.
Please take the time to read this Privacy Policy carefully. It is very important that you fully understand how we are processing your personal data, and how we are protecting your privacy. If you have any questions regarding our use of your
personal data, please contact us at either of the email addresses listed below:
General privacy and compliance: Privacy@Clearly.com.au
Data Protection Officer, Tim Desmond: Tim.Desmond@Clearly.com.au
WHAT PERSONAL DATA DO WE COLLECT?
Data we collect when you visit our website
When you access our website, we automatically collect and store some of your data in our server logs and in cookies, which are small text files that a web server stores in browser software. A browser sends cookies to a server when the browser
makes a connection to the server.
This data does not allow us to directly identify you, but it does record data related to your browsing history on our website. This includes the pages you accessed; the date and time of your request and referral URL; the date and time at which
you accessed them; your search queries within the site; and information about the device you used such as its hardware model, operation system version, unique device identifier, Internet protocol address, hardware settings, browser type, and
browser language.
You are not required to provide your data if you only want to visit our website. You may refuse to accept cookies by configuring your web browser accordingly (for more information, refer to the ‘help’ section of your web browser). That said,
refusing cookies is likely to disrupt your navigation on our website, and may prevent you from accessing certain pages or services.
Data we collect when you sign up or when you order products
Some of the services offered on our website require you to register and/or sign up with us. If
you want to use these services, we will ask you to provide us with complete and accurate
personal data, and inform us if, or when, your data needs to be updated. If you do not
provide us with complete and accurate data, or if you do not inform us that your data needs
to be updated, we may not be able to provide you with the services you have requested.
We collect the following categories of your personal data:
Identification data: including your name, telephone number, e-mail address,
Customer ID, Prescription, and similar information.
Financial data: including the details of your payment method such as a credit card,
though we do not store the details of any card after the first order has been
processed.
IT data: including the pages you accessed; the date and time of your request and
referral URL; the date and time at which you accessed them; your search queries
within the site; and information about the device you used such as its hardware
model, operation system version, unique device identifier, Internet protocol address,
hardware settings, browser type, and browser language.
HOW DO WE USE THE PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT?
We only use your personal data within the limits authorized by current laws and regulations.
Sometimes, we shall use your personal data because laws and regulations actively require us
to do so. In any case, we do not make any automated decisions solely on automatic
processing which may produce legal effects concerning you, or similarly significantly affect
you.
We use your personal data for the following purposes:
We use your identification data in order to provide you with services as per our
contractual obligations.
We use your financial data to process sales, returns, or replacement orders.
We use your IT data to track various analytics attributes so that we can continue to
provide a more efficient service.
HOW LONG DO WE KEEP THE PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT?
You can see the time limits for personal data storage below:
Identification data - 7 years
Financial data - 10 years
IT data - 7 years
WHAT PERSONAL DATA DO WE SHARE?
We inform you that we may share your personal data with companies outside of Clearly.
Identification data - Yes. Limited strictly to SMS (name and telephone no)
Financial data - No
IT data - Yes
HOW DO WE PROTECT PERSONAL DATA?
We have measures in place to protect your personal data against unauthorized access, use,
or disclosure, including without limitation:
We implement and maintain sophisticated technical measures to ensure that your
personal data is recorded and processed in complete confidentiality and security.
We implement and maintain appropriate restrictions on access to your personal data,
and monitoring of the access, use, and transfer of personal data.
All employees who have access to your personal data are required to enter into nondisclosure
or similar agreements, which imposes obligations for them to comply with
our data privacy and confidentiality requirements.
We require any business partners and third-party service providers with whom we
may share your personal data to comply with any applicable data privacy and
confidentiality requirements.
We provide data privacy training on a regular basis to our employees and third parties
who have access to personal data.
WHAT RIGHTS DO YOU HAVE?
Under applicable data protection laws and regulations, you have the following rights:
Of access to, rectification of, and/or erasure of your personal data;
To restrict or object to its processing;
To tell us that you do not wish to receive marketing information;
In some circumstances, to require certain of your personal data to be transferred to
you or a third party; and
To the extent our processing of your personal data is based upon your consent, to
withdraw your consent, without affecting the lawfulness of our processing based on
your consent before its withdrawal.
We are committed to enabling you full exercise of your rights: to do so, you can contact us
using the contact details indicated at the beginning of this Privacy Policy. Please provide us
with the following information so that we can take your request with all due consideration:
Your name and surname, and a photocopy of your identity card;
Your specific petition (in other words, what rights you want to exercise);
The date of the application and your signature (if you sent your application by postal
mail).
If you do not feel satisfied following this interaction, you may also lodge a complaint about
our processing of your Personal Data with a data protection authority.
Service-related Announcements
We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is
necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance,
we may send you an email. Generally, you may not opt out of these communications,
particularly as they are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you
have the option to deactivate your account.
Newsletters
If you wish to subscribe to our email newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address
to send the emails to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you an option to
unsubscribe. Please see the Opt Out section below.
Opt Out
We provide you the opportunity to opt out of having your personal information used for
certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you purchase a
product/service but do not wish to receive any additional promotional emails from us, you
may opt out at any time by following the unsubscribe link located at the bottom of each
email communication.
If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may
opt out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter.
Opt In
By accepting these terms and conditions, you (i) allow us to share your data strictly with
companies within Clearly and (ii) give your express, specific and informed consent to
receive emails of promotional materials concerning optical products and glasses from these
companies. Each email sent to you by Clearly and/or other companies within our
group will include an 'unsubscribe' link.
We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information
submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of
transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore,
while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information,
we cannot guarantee its absolute security.
Removing Display/Advertisements from Your Device
Option A
Go to the NAI website. Their site will scan your computer/device for any third-party display
or advertisements. A list of any third-party ads will then be populated and from there you
can select the checkboxes next to the ads that you would like to remove. This ensures that
advertisements will not come back to your computer/device as it is not registered to receive
them. Note, the NAI website is not associated with Clearly.
Option B
Manually access the cache and cookies of your browser and clear them. You will need to
clear all to remove all third-party display advertisements.
How to clear cookies and cache in Firefox
How to clear cookies and cache in Chrome
How to clear cookies and cache in Internet Explorer
CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY NOTICE
We regularly review our compliance with our Privacy Policy and apply updates to make it
compliant with new laws and regulations regarding data protection. But, even if this Privacy
Policy may change from time to time, we will not reduce your rights under this Privacy Policy
without your explicit consent.
Sign up for news and exclusive offers.
Your e-mail address
Sign Up
You can unsubscribe at any time. Please see our
privacy policy
Sign up successful!
You're good to go! Thank you for joining.
Looks like you’ve already subscribed!
Add us to your favorites so you don’t miss out
The Clearly Difference
Our Story
Our Mission
International Sites
United States
Canada
New Zealand
Healthfunds
Need your eyes checked?
1800 639 478 Clearly Coupon Codes
Eye Health
How to read your prescription
Eye Health FAQ’s Contact Lens Misconceptions Contact lens care
International Sites
United States
Canada
New Zealand
Copyright © 2020 Clearly. All rights reserved.
Terms & Conditions
Privacy Policy
Sitemap
New customers get 15% off first order of contacts & free shipping when you sign up for email
You can unsubscribe at any time. Please see our
Privacy Policy
Sign up
Please enter a valid email address.
You can unsubscribe at any time. Please see our
Privacy Policy
New customers get 15% off first order of contacts & free shipping when you sign up for email
Sign up for email to get code
Sign up»
We promise to never share your information.
Privacy Policy
Oz Contacts is now part of Clearly Australia
We're excited to share that Oz Contacts has merged with Clearly Australia, which means you can now shop for the contact lenses you already love, with plenty of new benefits.
Same awesome Aussie service - and so much more
Fast and free delivery
From our Sydney warehouse on every order
24/7 customer service
Contact us via phone, email, and live chat
Australia's #1
AU's biggest online contact lens, eyeglasses and sunglasses store
Learn more about joining the Clearly Australia family
Questions? We're here to help
Please get in touch with any queries or concerns. Our Vision Ambassadors are available 24/7 - call us at 1 800 639 478 or contact us online
Net Optical Australia is now part of Clearly Australia
We're excited to share that Net Optical Australia has merged with Clearly Australia, which means you can now shop for the contact lenses you already love, with plenty of new benefits.
Same awesome Aussie service - and so much more
Fast and free delivery
From our Sydney warehouse on every order
24/7 customer service
Contact us via phone, email, and live chat
Australia's #1
AU's biggest online contact lens, eyeglasses and sunglasses store
Learn more about joining the Clearly Australia family
Questions? We're here to help
Please get in touch with any queries or concerns. Our Vision Ambassadors are available 24/7 - call us at 1 800 639 478 or contact us online
WebContacts is now part of Clearly Australia
We're excited to share that WebContacts has merged with Clearly Australia, which means you can now shop for the contact lenses you already love, with plenty of new benefits.
Same awesome Aussie service - and so much more
Fast and free delivery
From our Sydney warehouse on every order
24/7 customer service
Contact us via phone, email, and live chat
Australia's #1
AU's biggest online contact lens, eyeglasses and sunglasses store
Learn more about joining the Clearly Australia family
Questions? We're here to help
Please get in touch with any queries or concerns. Our Vision Ambassadors are available 24/7 - call us at 1 800 639 478 or contact us online
YourContacts is now part of Clearly Australia
We're excited to share that YourContacts has merged with Clearly Australia, which means you can now shop for the contact lenses you already love, with plenty of new benefits.
Same awesome Aussie service - and so much more
Fast and free delivery
From our Sydney warehouse on every order
24/7 customer service
Contact us via phone, email, and live chat
Australia's #1
AU's biggest online contact lens, eyeglasses and sunglasses store
Learn more about joining the Clearly Australia family
Questions? We're here to help
Please get in touch with any queries or concerns. Our Vision Ambassadors are available 24/7 - call us at 1 800 639 478 or contact us online
